{
    "id": "4ecd0d6c23494b1ca0852d54e4b70e85",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If he ……………………. like this, he will have an accident one of these days.",
            "description": "Use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause to talk about real and possible situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "drives",
                "has driven",
                "drove"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she ……………………….. never forget me.",
            "description": "Would is the past form of will. When the main clause is in the past tense, the subordinate clause too should be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know where she …………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "is living",
                "has lived"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Though we played well, we …………………………. win the match.",
            "description": "Could not shows past inability.",
            "answers": [
                "cannot",
                "could not",
                "would not"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She accused me of ………………………… her letters.",
            "description": "A verb used after a preposition should be in its ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to read",
                "read",
                "reading"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I couldn’t remember if I ……………………… the door.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "locked",
                "have locked",
                "had locked"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She told me …………………….. lost.",
            "description": "Imperative sentences are reported with a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "to get",
                "getting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My parents always encouraged me …………………………. big.",
            "description": "Encourage is followed by object + to infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "dream",
                "dreaming",
                "to dream"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for hours but no one ………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "comes",
                "had come",
                "came"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had been more careful, the accident ……………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "could have avoided",
                "can be avoided",
                "could have been avoided"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She insisted that I …………………………. her.",
            "description": "This is an example of a subjunctive. Either go or should go is possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "should go",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you …………………………. calling me.",
            "description": "We use a past tense after would rather to refer to present or future. ",
            "answers": [
                "stop",
                "stopped",
                "had stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}